<DiscoveryMethod NAME="SNMP" 
                 VERSION="2.0" 
                 TYPE="NET" >
   <Display>
    <Description NLSID="placeholder">Discover targets by running scripts on remote node</Description>
   </Display>

   <DiscCode CODE_LOCATION="AGENT">
     <CodePackage PACKAGE_NAME="SnmpDM">
       <Dependency REQUIREMENT="JAVA" VERSION="1.4.2" />
     </CodePackage>
     <JavaImpl IMPLCLASS="oracle.sysman.emd.disc.snmp.SnmpScanDiscoveryMethod" 
               CLASSPATH="snmpdm.jar" />
   </DiscCode>

   <Signature NAME="ID_OID_NAME">
     <Display>
       <Description NLSID="placeholder">this is the SNMP object ID which is used to uniquely identify a service of the requested kind. It is given as a String.</Description>
     </Display>
     <ValueFormat TYPE="STRING" />
   </Signature>
   <Signature NAME="OIDS">
     <Display>
       <Description NLSID="placeholder">a list of additional object IDs which will be used to form the target name and the display name. This oids are defined as a string with the syntax &lt;name&gt;:&lt;oid&gt;[:indirect[string][=&lt;indoid&gt;]][:table] where name is a symbolic name of the oid which is used when building the target name and display name. Also these symbolic name are used when defining patterns to filter on the SNMP response (see VALUE_PATTERNS).
There is one already defined name sysDesc which is retrieved automatically.
indirect will use the value of oid as an oid to retrieve an indirect value, indoid if given will be used as a base for the redirected oid. indirectstring denotes a string index. The table keyword is used to describe snmp tables.</Description>
     </Display>
     <ValueFormat TYPE="LIST" />
   </Signature>
   <Signature NAME="VALUE_PATTERNS">
     <Display>
       <Description NLSID="placeholder">a list of regular expressions to be used to post-process the snmp responses before inserting them in the NAME_TEMPLATE and DISPLAY_TEMPLATE. The regular expressions are given in the following syntax: &lt;patname&gt;:&lt;name&gt;:&lt;regex&gt; where patname is the name of the pattern, name is the symbolic name of one of the oids defined in OIDS and regex is a regular expression as defined in java.util.regex</Description>
      </Display>
     <ValueFormat TYPE="LIST" />
    </Signature>
    <Signature NAME="NAME_TEMPLATE">
      <Display>
        <Description NLSID="placeholder">a string containing a template definition to build the target instance name. The template consists of static text and placeholders for the SNMP response values. The placeholder syntax is %&lt;name&gt;% where name is either a symbolic name defined in OIDS, sysdesc, or a pattern name.  There are also special placeholders %hostName% and %snmpPort% which will be replaced by the host name the services runs on and the inet port the service listenes on.</Description>
      </Display>
     <ValueFormat TYPE="STRING" />
   </Signature>
   <Signature NAME="DISPLAY_TEMPLATE">
     <Display>
       <Description NLSID="placeholder">a string containing a template definitions to build the target instance display name. (see NAME_TEMPLATE)</Description>
      </Display>
     <ValueFormat TYPE="STRING" />
    </Signature>
    <Signature NAME="TARGET_PROPERTIES">
      <Display>
        <Description NLSID="placeholder">a list of strings of the syntax &lt;property name&gt;:&lt;template&gt;. Where template is a definition for the property value with the same rules as NAME_TEMPLATE.</Description>
      </Display>
     <ValueFormat TYPE="LIST" />
    </Signature>
    <Signature NAME="PATTERN_DEFAULTS">
      <Display>
        <Description NLSID="placeholder">a list of default values for patterns if the regular expression does not match. The syntax is &lt;pattern_name&gt;:&lt;default value&gt; A default value is optional.</Description>
      </Display>
     <ValueFormat TYPE="LIST" />
    </Signature>
    <Signature NAME="SNMP_VERSION">
      <Display>
       <Description NLSID="placeholder">the snmp protocol version.</Description>
      </Display>
     <ValueFormat TYPE="STRING" />
    </Signature>
    <Signature NAME="VERSION">
      <Display>
       <Description NLSID="placeholder">a string containing the plug-in version.</Description>
      </Display>
     <ValueFormat TYPE="STRING" />
    </Signature>

    <ConfigParam NAME="SNMP_PORTS">
      <Display>
        <Description NLSID="placeholder">a list of SNMP ports to query for. The default is 161.
	</Description>
      </Display>
     <ValueFormat TYPE="LIST" />
    </ConfigParam>
    <ConfigParam NAME="TIMEOUT">
      <Display>
        <Description NLSID="placeholder">a number which gives the timeout for udp responses. The value is given in milliseconds and the default is 2000.
	</Description>
      </Display>
     <ValueFormat TYPE="NUMBER" />
    </ConfigParam>
    <ConfigParam NAME="PARALLELIZATION_LEVEL">
      <Display>
        <Description NLSID="placeholder">the level of parallelization which is the number of threads to query the network. The default is 256.
        </Description>
      </Display>
     <ValueFormat TYPE="NUMBER" />
    </ConfigParam>
    <ConfigParam NAME="SNMP_COMMUNITY">
      <Display>
        <Description NLSID="placeholder">the snmp community string to use.  The default is 'public'.
        </Description>
      </Display>
     <ValueFormat TYPE="STRING" />
    </ConfigParam>

</DiscoveryMethod>


